{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "This poem, which was written on a trip to visit the father of the author’s lover Chester Kallman, was read on NPR following the 9/11 attacks. The “Daisy” Ad uses a variation of the final line from this poem, which states “We must love each other, or we must die.” This poem’s author claims he was “in one of the dives / On Fifty-second Street” when he heard the news of Germany invading Poland. For ten points, name this W.H. Auden poem written at, and named for, the start of World War II.",
      "answer": "September 1, 1939"
    },
    {
      "question": "The founder of this group, John Elder, was sometimes called the Fighting Parson for his knack of keeping a rifle while delivering sermons. Benjamin Franklin’s “Narrative of the Late Massacres” claims that attacks carried out by this group were more savage than those of their victims, the Conestoga and Susquehannock. After failing to receive government support, this group undertook a 1764 march on Philadelphia. For ten points, name this group of Scottish and Irish immigrants on the Pennsylvania frontier.",
      "answer": "Paxton Boys"
    },
    {
      "question": "In demonstrating that dead yeast cells produced sugar via these things, Eduard Buchner disputed Louis Pasteur’s view that living cells were needed for fermentation. In 2018, Frances Arnold won the Nobel Prize in Chemistry for her work in engineering these things. The presence of one of these things named rennet allowed ancient Egyptians who stored milk in dried stomachs to create cheese. The suffix ase [spell it] is usually used in the names of, for ten points, what biological macromolecules that speed up chemical reactions?",
      "answer": "enzymes"
    },
    {
      "question": "A key leader of this movement had a brother who helped win the Battle of Ayacucho and founded the newspaper Northern Star. This movement included striking miners in Cornwall in the Plug Plot Riots. Feargus O’Connor led this movement, which indirectly increased suffrage via the 1867 Great Reform Bill. This movement called for secret ballots and annual elections for Parliament. For ten points, name this 19th century British working class movement for political reform that called for the vote for all men over age 21.",
      "answer": [
        "Chartism",
        "word forms, like Chartists"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Bill Anthrell hosted an event at this university at which he claimed he was going to kill a dog with napalm. A lawsuit following the most famous event at this university targeted then-governor Jim Rhodes, who sent the National Guard to this university. Contrary to popular belief, a 14-year old runaway was not a student of this university, despite being depicted in a photograph next to one of the four students killed on May 4, 1970. For ten points, name this Ohio university where Vietnam War protesters were infamously shot.",
      "answer": "Kent State University"
    },
    {
      "question": "An infamous doctrine developed by this man prevented the extradition of terrorists back to Italy. This man signed the Gayssot Act to make denial of the Holocaust illegal. This man controversially ordered Operation Satan, the bombing of the Greenpeace ship Rainbow Warrior in New Zealand waters. This leader’s tenure featured two cohabitations with Edouard Balladur and Jacques Chirac. For ten points, name this first socialist president of France.",
      "answer": "Francois Mitterand"
    },
    {
      "question": "Description not acceptable; this has a name. The main inhabitant of this facility lived in the first of three security zones in an area protected from direct exposure to the sun. The Todt Organization built this facility near the town of Rastenberg in the Masurian woods. An assassination attempt at this location was known as Operation Valkyrie and failed on July 20, 1944, a few months before its occupant left it for an underground bunker in Berlin. For ten points, name this fortified residence that served as Hitler’s headquarters on the Eastern Front.",
      "answer": "Wolf’s Lair or Wolfsschanze"
    },
    {
      "question": "At its 1931 opening, this bridge surpassed the Ambassador Bridge as the longest bridge in the world. This bridge, which was originally slated to be named the Knickerbocker Bridge, terminates at Fort Lee on one side. For a week in September 2013, two of this bridge’s three lanes were closed during rush hour traffic, a political punishment for Mark Sokolich for not supporting Chris Christie’s run for Governor of New Jersey. For ten points, name this bridge across the Hudson River.",
      "answer": [
        "George Washington Bridge",
        "GWB",
        "GW Bridge"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This war, which was concentrated along the Daya River, was won by a king referred to in some texts as Priyadarsi. This war ended with a successful “mission of the peace,” according to the author of Military History of Orissa. The successor to Bindusara started this war, whose victor decided to devote himself to the principle of ahimsa, or non-violence. According to the thirteenth Rock Edict, over 150,000 members of the losing kingdom were killed by the Mauryans in, for ten points, what war that led Ashoka to convert to Buddhism?",
      "answer": "Kalinga War"
    },
    {
      "question": "The losing side’s strategy during this battle was known as Plan A-Go. Despite the risk of submarine attacks, Marc Mitscher heroically turned on the lights of his flight decks to help fighter pilots return to safety during this battle. In a debriefing aboard the USS Lexington a pilot compared this battle to an “old-time” event “down home,” hence providing the nickname “Great Marianas Turkey Shoot.” The last carrier-on-carrier battle between the U.S. and Japan was, for ten points, what battle fought in a body of water bordering Mindanao?",
      "answer": [
        "Battle of the Philippine Sea",
        "Great Marianas Turkey Shoot before mentioned"
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "While this man was meeting with Ho Chi Minh, Operation Cold Chop led to the capture of the Flagstaff House and this man’s overthrow. Shortly after this man’s Convention People’s Party won a rigged election, he was deposed by Joseph Ankrah in a coup. This man, who gave the “Motion of Destiny” speech in support of independence, joined Nasser as an African founder of the Non-Aligned Movement. The Akosombo Dam was built in the former Gold Coast under the leadership of, for ten points, what first president of Ghana?",
        "answer": "Kwame Nkrumah"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Nkrumah built the Akosombo Dam on this African river; the dam then created the world’s largest artificial lake behind it, a lake that shares its name with this river.",
        "answer": [
          "Volta River",
          "Lake Volta"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "At the Battle of Cap Bon, this group killed over 10,000 Roman soldiers. These people’s king Godigisel died while this group crossed the Rhine River with the Alans and the Suebi. This Germanic tribe fought Belisarius at the Battle of Ad Decimum and Tricamarum near their capital of Carthage. The Hasdingi and Silingi formed this group, which invaded Iberia before conquering North Africa. For ten points, name these Germanic people whose name sounds like a criminal that destroys property.",
        "answer": "Vandals"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This last Germanic ruler of the Vandals deposed Hilderic and twice fled after facing off against Belisarius at Ad Decimum and Tricamarum.",
        "answer": "Gelimer"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This politician was removed as the head of the Foreign Relations Committee after spearheading resistance against the annexation of the Dominican Republic. In his most famous oration, this politician noted his rival had a “mistress, who though ugly to others, is lovely to him,” then compared that rival to Don Quixote. This man was confronted for producing “libel on South Carolina” before he was physically attacked for his speech “The Crime Against Kansas.” For ten points, name this Massachusetts Senator who was caned on the Senate floor by Preston Brooks.",
        "answer": "Charles Sumner"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Charles Sumner declared “the harlot, Slavery” to be the mistress of this South Carolina senator in the “Crime Against Kansas” speech. A US Marine Corps general with the same surname warned Congress of the Business Plot, a coup against FDR.",
        "answer": [
          "Butler",
          "Andrew Butler and/or Smedley Butler"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The philosopher Kundakunda is a major figure in a sect of this religion that believes that women cannot escape the cycle of rebirth and that the original scriptures of this religion have been lost. Members of that sect of this religion, the Digambara or “sky-clad,” do not wear clothes, while their counterparts, the Svetambara wear white robes; members of both sects carry around feather brooms for sweeping away insects. For ten points, name this Indian religion which observes the “ahimsa” principle of radical non-violence.",
        "answer": "Jainism"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Suicide is only allowed in Jainism through the Sallekhana rite, which involves killing oneself through this method.",
        "answer": [
          "fasting",
          "equivalent descriptions related to not eating food]"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "During the lockout-shortened 1999 season, this team lost in the NBA Finals despite entering the playoffs as an 8 seed. This team lost the 1994 NBA Finals, and its win in Game 5 of that series was televised in a small box in the corner while the majority of the screen covered the ongoing OJ Simpson low-speed car chase. Patrick Ewing played 15 seasons for, for ten points, what NBA team that is owned by James Dolan’s Madison Square Garden Company?",
        "answer": [
          "New York Knicks",
          "either",
          "both names"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The 1998-99 NBA lockout was one of four work stoppages during the tenure of this NBA commissioner, who held the job for 30 years until being succeeded by Adam Silver in 2014. Conspiracy theorists hold that this man froze the Knicks’ envelope in the 1985 Draft Lottery, helping them win the first pick to draft Patrick Ewing.",
        "answer": "David Stern"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Linda Nash received over $5 million dollars for injuries received during this event, which resulted in six deaths. A tip given to Bill Miller of the Diplomatic Security Service resulted in the capture of this event’s perpetrator, who said “I am a terrorist and proud of it” during his trial. Eyad Ismoil was involved in this event, which targeted the B-2 level of a parking garage in Manhattan. Ramzi Yousef carried out, for ten points, what 1993 terrorist attack in New York City?",
        "answer": [
          "1993 World Trade Center bombing",
          "descriptions of the 1993 WTC attack,",
          "the first WTC attack",
          "Twin Towers in place of WTC"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Five of the six fatalities in the World Trade Center bombing were employees of this organization, which operates the airports, tunnels, and bridges of the New York/New Jersey area. 84 of its employees were killed on 9/11.",
        "answer": "Port Authority of New York & New Jersey"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In 2000, a leader of this ethnicity was assassinated while filling out a football betting slip in the lobby of the Intercontinental Hotel. Members of this ethnicity formed the White Eagles and the Volunteer Guard, the latter of which was better known as Arkan’s Tigers. The Scorpions, who were of this ethnicity, wereledbyRatkoMladic[m’lah-ditch]inperpetratingtheSrebrenica[sreh-breh-neetzah]massacreagainst Bosniaks in the Yugoslav Wars. For ten points, name this Southern Slavic ethnic group, the majority ethnic group in Belgrade.",
        "answer": [
          "Serbs",
          "Serbians, despite minor differences between the terms"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "After being indicted for war crimes, this first President of Republika Srpska was on the run for 12 years before being arrested while disguised in Belgrade. This man and Ratko Mladic were convicted of the Srebrenica massacre.",
        "answer": "Radovan Karadzic , but be lenient"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man’s press secretary, Andr´e Singer, transformed this man’s name into a term for a no-conflict, stable ideology. After leaving office at the end of 2010, this man’s appointment as Chief of Staff under his successor was blocked by Gilmar Mendes [zheel-mar men-des]. A $1.1 million apartment was found to have been given to this man as a bribe as part of an investigation known as Operation Car Wash. This former leader of the Workers’ Party was jailed after being convicted on money laundering charges in 2017. For ten points, name this predecessor of Dilma Rousseff as President of Brazil.",
        "answer": [
          "Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva",
          "either",
          "both underlined parts"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This judge sentenced Lula da Silva and many other criminals investigated by Operation Car Wash. In 2018, this man accepted the post of Justice Minister under Jair Bolsonaro.",
        "answer": "Sergio Moro"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "America’s Westward Expansion",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Nickname for California gold rushers, based on the second year of the rush.",
          "answer": "49ers"
        },
        {
          "question": "Short-lived mail carrier service that employed hundreds of horses to make quick exchanges between stations.",
          "answer": "Pony Express"
        },
        {
          "question": "Phrase coined by John O’Sullivan to advocate the annexation of Texas, as it was America’s divine right to control the continent.",
          "answer": "manifest destiny"
        },
        {
          "question": "1862 law that granted millions of acres to small farmers, commonly 160 acres at a time.",
          "answer": "Homestead Act or Law, etc."
        },
        {
          "question": "Ranching equipment, developed by Joseph Glidden, that made enclosure of grazing land possible.",
          "answer": "barbed wire"
        },
        {
          "question": "Firearms company whose Model 1873 rifle was the “Gun that Won the West.”",
          "answer": [
            "Winchester Repeating Arms Company",
            "descriptions of Winchester rifles"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "TheoryproposedbyFrederickJacksonTurnertoexplainchangesindemocracyasAmericanexpansion progressed.",
          "answer": "Frontier thesis"
        },
        {
          "question": "Fur trapper and colleague of John Fremont who led thousands of Navajo on the forced “Long Walk” to Bosque Redondo.",
          "answer": "Christopher “Kit” Carson"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Modern German Politics",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Center-right party, the traditional rival of the Social Democratic Party, that currently holds power.",
          "answer": [
            "Christian Democratic Party of Germany",
            "Christian Democrats",
            "CDU",
            "Christlich Demokratische Union Deutschlands"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Current Chancellor of Germany, the first woman to hold the position.",
          "answer": "Angela Merkel"
        },
        {
          "question": "Elected Parliament of Germany, which meets in the Reichstag in Berlin.",
          "answer": "Bundestag"
        },
        {
          "question": "Environmentalist party that merged with Alliance 90 in 1993.",
          "answer": [
            "Alliance 90/The Greens",
            "Green Party",
            "Bu¨ndnis 90/Die Gru¨nen"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Racist, far-right party founded in 2013 that won its first 94 seats in Parliament in 2017.",
          "answer": [
            "Alternative for Germany or AfD",
            "Alternative fu¨r Deutschland"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Chancellor of West Germany whose Finance Minister Ludwig Erhard engineered an “economic miracle” after the war.",
          "answer": "Konrad Adenauer"
        },
        {
          "question": "Chancellor who led reunified Germany after the fall of the Berlin Wall.",
          "answer": "Helmut Kohl"
        },
        {
          "question": "Current President of German Parliament and former Finance Minister who resigned as party leader in 2000 amidst scandal.",
          "answer": "Wolfgang Schauble , but be lenient"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Second Sino-Japanese War",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Mountain range between China and India that Allied pilots flew over to supply Chinese forces.",
          "answer": "Himalayan Mountains"
        },
        {
          "question": "Five-member body of the United Nations that China was admitted to during the war.",
          "answer": "UN Security Council"
        },
        {
          "question": "War between the Nationalists and Communists that was paused by the war against Japan.",
          "answer": "Chinese Civil War"
        },
        {
          "question": "Capital of the Republic of China, the site of a 1937 massacre.",
          "answer": "Nanjing or Nanking"
        },
        {
          "question": "First Lady who visited America several times to rally support for her husband’s war effort.",
          "answer": [
            "Soong Mei-ling",
            "Madame Chiang"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "1931 incident involving dynamite near a railway that led to a Japanese invasion of Manchuria.",
          "answer": [
            "Mukden incident",
            "Liutiaohu incident"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Bridge southwest of Beijing where a 1937 incident marked the start of the war.",
          "answer": "Marco Polo Bridge or Lugou Bridge"
        },
        {
          "question": "Major 1944 Japanese offensive aimed at opening a land route to Indochina, after which Joseph Stilwell was removed.",
          "answer": "Operation Ichi-Go"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) After this man failed to gain support for a bill legalizing denomination-based boarding schools, he was replaced in his post by Botho zu Eulenburg. The Agrarian League opposed this man for his support of free trade. Though he was able to secure Heligoland in an exchange for (20 pts)",
        "Zanzibar, this man failed to renew his predecessor’s Reinsurance Treaty with Russia. This man’s “New Course” policy aimed to improve relations with Great Britain, who ceded a (10 pts)",
        "Namibian strip named for this man to Germany. For ten points, name this successor of Otto von Bismarck as chancellor."
      ],
      "answer": "Leo von Caprivi"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This city’s school system was the subject of the Milliken v. Bradley desegregation case in 1974. In the early 1980s, this city seized nearly 500 acres of private land in Poletown to build the Hamtramck factory, a move supported by mayor (20 pts)",
        "Coleman Young. Governor Rick Snyder seized financial control over this city in March 2013; four months later, it (10 pts)",
        "declared bankruptcy, the largest US city to do so in history. White flight to suburbs like the Grosse Pointes and Troy has affected, for ten points, what largest city in Michigan?"
      ],
      "answer": "Detroit"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Limestone blocks cut into smaller talatats were used to construct this place, which some scholars believe was named a capital city because the shape of its “Great Wadi” resembles a symbol meaning “horizon.” In this city, a bust of a woman whose husband was purged from historical records was sculpted by (20 pts)",
        "Thutmose. A relief from this city is a “window of appearance” scene, where seated parents receive “life-giving (10 pts)",
        "rays” from ankhs extending from a solar disc. The pharaoh Akhenaten established, for ten points, what Egyptian city that became the center of his cult of worshiping Aten?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Amarna",
        "Akhetaten"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This leader undertook a radical anti-inflation program despite pledging not to do so in a competitive 1990 election campaign; the program led to what became known as his namesake “shock.” This leader was toppled by the “Vladivideos,” in which (20 pts)",
        "Vladimiro Montesinos admitted to corruption. This leader defeated a guerrilla group led by Abimael Guzman as well as a general election campaign by (10 pts)",
        "Mario Vargas Llosa. This man’s children Keiko and Kenji serve in his country’s senate, despite this man’s imprisonment on corruption charges. For ten points, name this Japanese-descended former dictator of Peru."
      ],
      "answer": "Alberto Fujimori"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This philosopher argued that, since a point is a place in space that takes up no space, it is best defined as “a negation of itself.” Karl Popper argued that the political philosophy of this one-time roommate of Schelling and Holderlin was a thinly veiled defense of (20 pts)",
        "Frederick William III. A philosophical circle which included Max Stirner were the so called “Young” followers of this thinker, in whose system a (10 pts)",
        "“thesis” and “antithesis” sublate into a “synthesis.” For ten points, name this philosopher who espoused his dialectical system in The Science of Logic and The Phenomenology of Spirit."
      ],
      "answer": "Georg Wilhelm Friedrich Hegel"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This composer requested no applause at the premiere of one of his works, which opens with a movement juxtaposing the Kyrie [keer-ee-ay] with the tenor solo “What passing bells for those who (20 pts)",
        "die as cattle?” Wilfred Owen poetry is used in that work, which this man helped conduct at its premiere at the re-consecration of (10 pts)",
        "Coventry Cathedral. Another work by this composer displays the various sections of an orchestra for children. For ten points, name this British composer of War Requiem and The Young Person’s Guide to the Orchestra."
      ],
      "answer": "Benjamin Britten"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The name of the central group in this event was inspired by a French saying meaning “Comrade, let’s get a drink.” A man known as Ser Nuto was hung by one foot during this event. The Eight Saints were defeated during this event, whose leader was chosen after he walked barefoot into a palace. A group of (20 pts)",
        "butchers carried out an attack in the Piazza della Signoria during this event. Michele [mik-ay-lay] di Lando became the (10 pts)",
        "Gonfaloniere during this event, which was partly caused by anger at the quadrupling of guild entry fees. For ten points, name this 1378 revolt of Florentine woolworkers."
      ],
      "answer": "Ciompi Revolt"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Description acceptable. During this campaign, George A. Dodd led the so-called “last true cavalry charge.” An officer in this campaign strapped two captured soldiers on the hood of his car and carved three notches in his pistols. Four “flying columns” were dispatched during this campaign, which saw fighting at the town of (20 pts)",
        "Parral and the use of Buffalo Soldiers at Guerrero. A´lvaro Obreg´on threatened to attack this (10 pts)",
        "expedition, which began after the Division of the North attacked Columbus, New Mexico. For ten points, name this 1916-17 expedition led by John Pershing, a failed attempt to capture a Mexican soldier."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Punitive Expedition",
        "descriptions of John “Blackjack” Pershing’s expedition to capture Pancho Villa"
      ]
    }
  ]
}